<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ken Bellows</title>
    <description>These are some thoughts on life, code, politics, philosophy, technology, and whatever else happens to be on my mind.
</description>
    <link>http://kenbellows.github.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://kenbellows.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 15:36:11 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 15:36:11 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Look At My Son</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/emerson_2016-06-28.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My son, Emerson&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today my son, Emerson, is 34 days old. I am terrified of being a father.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a person who has a difficult time feeling emotions. I don’t mean that I have a hard time processing my emotions; I think I’ve got a pretty solid handle on that. I mean that I really have a difficult time feeling them to begin with. At the risk of self-psychoanalysis, I figure this is caused by a combination of years of pushing down emotions to avoid ridicule in social situations (which, given my deep lack of social aptitude, was frequent enough without adding “crybaby” to my reputation) and the fact that my family seems to follow that long tradition, presumably descended from our ancient British ancestry and my parents’ deeply conservative backgrounds, of not really talking much about emotional things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that I recognize the lack of emotions in myself where others seems to find them means that I’m constantly questioning whether I’m reacting properly to my situation. When my son was born, I found that some tenth of my brain was always sitting in the background meta-analyzing the rest of my thoughts, constantly asking whether I was emotional enough.  Having a baby is supposed to be an emotional roller-coaster, right? Why was I so calm? Sure, I started to tear up a little when he emerged from the birth canal and my wife held him for the first time, but just barely; should I be crying? I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to cry; why aren’t I crying?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to be a good father, but I don’t really know what that means. I work full time, and I’m an easily distracted person when I’m home, so already I worry that I’m not spending enough time with him or paying enough attention to him. I desperately don’t want to be a father that remains distant and detached, only getting involved when asked. I want to be deeply involved in my son’s life, especially in these early days, but I just don’t know how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somtimes I also think I’m overthinking the whole situation and I should just relax and let things happen naturally. But then again, what comes naturally may not be the best way to do things (probably isn’t, in fact; I think I have a lot of learning to do). So I need to think and analyze to make sure I’m doing it right. But overthinking can lead to mistakes, stress, and self-degredation, none of which is good for him either. So how much thinking is enough but not too much? Am I overthinking overthinking?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, all I’ve learned so far is that I really have no idea what I’m doing, and I don’t know if I’m okay with that. I guess I’ll find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;bigquote&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;bigquote&quot;&gt;
    ...when you smile I am undone, my son; &lt;br /&gt;
    Look at my son! Pride is not the word I’m looking for; &lt;br /&gt;
    There is so much more inside me now
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;footer&gt;
    &amp;mdash; &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/vjMN6zSVFQg&quot;&gt;&quot;Dear Theodosia&quot;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Hamilton&lt;/i&gt; Soundtrack&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 10:21:40 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://kenbellows.github.io/blog/life/2016/06/29/look-at-my-son.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kenbellows.github.io/blog/life/2016/06/29/look-at-my-son.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
